The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: Erik and I
SRINI DEVADAS教授：我和Erik
have been tag teaming this lecture in this class
在本节课中一直在标记分组此讲座
so we're going to split this lecture.
所以我们将拆分本讲座。
So I get to do the first 2 minutes.
所以我开始做前2分钟。
No.
没有。
I get to do the first 20 minutes, or so,
我要开始大约20分钟的时间，
talking about some of my research
谈论我的一些研究
in parallel architecture.
在并行架构中。
And Erik's going to talk about a bunch of things
埃里克（Erik）将谈论一堆事情
that he's been up to over the years in Algorithm Design
他在算法设计领域工作了多年
and Analysis.
和分析。
So let's get started.
因此，让我们开始吧。
When was the first PC built, anybody?
第一台PC是何时制造的，有人吗？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: In the 1950s.
听众：在1950年代。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: No.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：不。
The first personal computer was 1981-- not the first computer.
第一台个人计算机是1981年，而不是第一台计算机。
So all of you know about Intel, and Microsoft, and IBM,
因此，你们所有人都了解英特尔，微软和IBM，
and so on.
等等。
Intel's gift to humankind is the x86 architecture.
英特尔给人类的礼物是x86架构。
Though, some people would argue that point.
虽然，有些人会争论这一点。
And the x86 architecture was invented in 1981,
x86架构是1981年发明的，
and was part of the first PC-- that provided the horsepower
并且是第一台PC的一部分-提供了强大的功能
for the first PC-- the IBM PC.
第一台PC-IBM PC。
And it ran at 5 megahertz.
它的运行频率为5兆赫。
And x86 has been around-- you still can buy x86 computers.
x86已经存在-您仍然可以购买x86计算机。
The 80486, in 1989, ran at 25 megahertz.
1989年的80486以25兆赫的频率运行。
So you can see a trend here.
这样您就可以在这里看到趋势。
And the 80486, as it turns out, ended up
事实证明，80486最终
being called the I486 because there was a court ruling that
之所以被称为I486，是因为法院裁定
said that you couldn't trademark numbers.
说你不能注册商标。
And so Intel, at that point, decided
因此，英特尔当时决定
to start naming their processors.
开始命名他们的处理器。
So the Pentium, which is one of the more famous Intel
奔腾（Pentium）是最著名的英特尔之一
processors, was built and came out in 1993.
处理器，于1993年问世。
And the clock speed went up to 66 megahertz,
时钟速度高达66兆赫，
back in the early '90s.
早在90年代初期。
And since this is just such a cool name,
由于这是一个很酷的名字，
Intel continued to call its processors Pentium.
英特尔继续称其处理器为奔腾。
And the Pentium 4, in 2000, had this incredibly deep pipeline
而在2000年的Pentium 4拥有如此难以置信的深度
where you broke up the computation
在哪里分手计算
into a bunch of stages.
进入多个阶段
In fact, it had a 30 stage pipeline.
实际上，它有30个阶段的管道。
And so the clock speed went up all the way to 1.5 gigahertz.
因此，时钟速度一直上升到1.5 GHz。
The Pentium was famous for many things,
奔腾（Pentium）以许多东西而闻名
including a couple of bugs in the floating point
包括浮点中的几个错误
pipeline where division, in particular corner cases,
分割的管道，特别是在极端情况下，
wasn't done correctly.
没有正确完成。
And there was also this bug called the F00F bug, which
还有一个叫做F00F的错误，
allowed a malicious program to crash the entire system,
允许恶意程序使整个系统崩溃，
regardless of whether it had administrative privileges
不管它是否具有管理权限
or not.
或不。
But the Pentium was obviously very successful.
但是奔腾显然很成功。
A lot of machines sold.
出售了很多机器。
And it felt like it was only going to be a matter of time
感觉这只是时间问题
before we got to 10s of gigahertz,
在我们达到10兆赫兹之前
the way things were going.
事情的进展。
As you can see, this is a pretty steep growth
如您所见，这是一个非常陡峭的增长
from 5 megahertz to 25 to 1.5 gigahertz
从5兆赫兹到25到1.5吉赫兹
in the space of about 20 years.
在大约20年的时间里。
As it turns out, after the Pentium D, which came out
事实证明，在奔腾D之后，
in 2005, where the clock speed peaked at about 3.2 gigahertz,
在2005年，时钟速度达到了约3.2 GHz的峰值，
clock frequency stopped increasing.
时钟频率停止增加。
And what you see now are things that
现在您所看到的是
correspond to multiple processors on a chip.
对应一个芯片上的多个处理器。
So for example, the Quad Core Xeon came out in 2008.
例如，Quad Core Xeon于2008年问世。
You can still buy it.
您仍然可以购买。
Only runs at 3 gigahertz, which is basically
仅以3 GHz的频率运行，这基本上是
about the same as the Pentium D ran.
与奔腾D的运行大致相同。
Each of these has a range of frequencies.
这些每个都有一个频率范围。
And beyond about 2005, the clock speed
大约在2005年以后，时钟速度
of processors that you can buy is kind of
您可以购买的处理器种类
saturated at about 3 gigahertz.
在约3 GHz时饱和。
And the way you're getting performance
以及您获得绩效的方式
is by putting multiple processors on the chip.
是通过在芯片上放置多个处理器来实现的。
And people use the term cores synonymously with processors.
人们将术语“核心”与处理器同义使用。
So a quad core means that they're, in effect,
因此，四核意味着它们实际上是
four x86 processors on the same silicon integrated circuit.
同一硅集成电路上的四个x86处理器。
And they're interconnected together.
它们相互连接在一起。
And they talk to memory.
他们谈论记忆。
And you have, essentially, a parallel processor
从本质上讲，您具有并行处理器
on a single chip.
在单个芯片上。
And the single user, potentially running many programs,
而单个用户（可能正在运行许多程序）
is using this system.
正在使用此系统。
And you have dual core processors on your laptops.
而且您的笔记本电脑上有双核处理器。
And so the scale, now, is-- the metric now,
因此，比例现在是-现在的指标，
I should say-- is how many cores do you have on a chip.
我应该说-一个芯片上有多少个内核。
And people are predicting that we're
人们预测我们
going to have 1,000 cores by 2020, on a chip.
到2020年将在芯片上拥有1,000个内核。
So this brings us to the problem of how do we use parallelism.
因此，这给我们带来了如何使用并行性的问题。
So there's a lot of work in parallel algorithms.
因此，并行算法有很多工作。
And there's also work in building hardware,
还有在构建硬件方面的工作，
such that algorithms can sort of automatically
这样算法可以自动排序
be parallelized while they're running in hardware,
在硬件中运行时进行并行化，
so they can run faster, and so on and so forth.
这样它们可以运行得更快，依此类推。
So some of my research is in parallel architecture.
因此，我的一些研究涉及并行体系结构。
Some of it is in parallel algorithms.
其中一些是并行算法。
I want to give you a sense of what the problems are
我想给你一个问题所在
in building parallel architectures.
在构建并行体系结构中。
And in particular, I'll start with a canonical system that
特别是，我将从一个规范的系统开始
corresponds to, let's say, this quad core system.
对应于这个四核系统。
And so you have 4 processors on this single integrated circuit.
因此，在此单个集成电路上您具有4个处理器。
So that signifies that.
这表明了这一点。
And typically, you have a lot of fast, static random-access
通常，您有很多快速，静态的随机访问
memory, SRAM, on the same chip.
内存，SRAM，在同一芯片上。
So typically, megabytes of the memory
因此通常情况下，兆字节的内存
on the chip and gigabytes of memory in DRAM,
在芯片上以及DRAM中的千兆字节内存中，
which are separate modules that are connected
是连接的独立模块
via high speed bus, off the chip.
通过高速总线，不在芯片上。
So there are usually many DRAM modules.
因此，通常有许多DRAM模块。
They're called DIMMS-- if you might have heard the term.
他们称为DIMMS-如果您可能听说过该术语。
So the connection between the processors and the SRAM
因此，处理器与SRAM之间的连接
is typically very fast.
通常非常快。
It's on-chip.
它在芯片上。
Things being clocked at gigahertz.
事情发生在千兆赫兹。
And when you go off-chip, you're down
当你离开芯片时，你就倒下了
to a few hundred megahertz.
到几百兆赫兹
So typically, an order of magnitude less speed.
因此通常速度要低一个数量级。
But you're accessing much more memory.
但是您正在访问更多的内存。
So this is really gigabytes and this
所以这真的是千兆字节
is at the level of megabytes.
处于兆字节级别。
If you see this picture, here-- if you
如果您看到这张图片，请在这里-如果您
think about the number of processors increasing
考虑处理器数量的增加
from four to eight to 16, all the way to,
从四到八到十六，一直到
say, to hundreds of processors, you
例如，对于数百个处理器，您
can see that there's going to be a bottleneck associated
可以看到会有瓶颈
with accessing the memory.
访问内存。
The big problem is you can't possibly
最大的问题是你不可能
build memory that serves hundreds
建立服务数百个的内存
of requests in parallel.
并行请求。
If you try and make a large SRAM, which is megabytes long,
如果您尝试制作一个长兆字节的大型SRAM，
the number of ports in the SRAM--
SRAM中的端口数-
read ports-- is roughly of the order of four.
读取端口-大约是四个数量级。
And after that it's kind of hard to build.
之后，就很难构建了。
So this architecture isn't going to be sustainable beyond 4, 8,
因此，这种架构在4、8之后无法持续
maybe 16 cores.
也许16核。
So typically, what people build is--
因此，通常情况下，人们建造的是-
or people are trying to build in academia--
或人们正在努力建立学术界-
is something that corresponds to a distributed architecture
与分布式架构相对应
on the chip, where you have processors and memory in tiles.
在芯片上，您可以在图块中拥有处理器和内存。
So you have, essentially, something
所以本质上来说，
like this, where you can imagine having literally 100
这样，您可以想象一下实际上有100个
processors on a chip that correspond to an implementation
芯片上与实现相对应的处理器
where you build tiles, where you have a processor that's
在哪里建造瓷砖，在哪里有一个处理器
doing the computation, and you have memory-- sometimes
进行计算，您就有了记忆-有时
called cache memory.
称为缓存。
But there's multiple levels of caches, typically, that
但是通常有多个级别的缓存
are attached to each of these processors.
被连接到每个这些处理器。
And the space between the processor tiles
以及处理器磁贴之间的空间
is reserved for interconnect or for wires
保留用于互连或电线
that connect these processors up.
将这些处理器连接起来。
And so there's research that goes on in routing algorithms.
因此，在路由算法中正在进行研究。
How you figure out if these processors want
您如何确定这些处理器是否需要
to talk to each other; what the best way of routing
互相交谈什么是最好的路由方式
the messages are; you want to find the shortest path.
消息是;您想找到最短的路径。
In this case, the weight corresponds
在这种情况下，权重对应
to the congestion that's associated
与相关的拥堵有关
with each of these channels that you have.
与您拥有的每个渠道。
And people actually use algorithms
人们实际上使用算法
like weighted shortest paths, in hardware,
例如加权的最短路径，在硬件中，
to determine what the best way of getting from here to there
确定从这里到达那里的最佳方法
is.
是。
It may not be this way.
可能不是这样。
It may be going around the chip simply
它可能只是绕过芯片
because that path-- the latter one is less congested.
因为那条路-后一条路比较不拥挤。
The other issue that comes up has
出现的另一个问题是
to do with how long it takes to go across the chip
与跨芯片需要多长时间有关
and come back.
再回来
So if this processor wants to access its local memory--
因此，如果该处理器要访问其本地内存，
that's typically pretty simple or fast.
这通常非常简单或快速。
But if it wants to access remote memory--
但是，如果要访问远程内存，
and it's quite possible that it's
而且很有可能
sharing some data with a different thread running
与运行中的其他线程共享一些数据
on a different processor.
在不同的处理器上。
So typically, there's a program running
所以通常情况下，有一个程序正在运行
on this processor, sometimes called a thread,
在此处理器（有时称为线程）上，
and this program may share data with a different program, which
并且该程序可能与其他程序共享数据，
is running on this processor.
在此处理器上运行。
Or it may just require a lot more space.
或者它可能只需要更多空间。
And what this program has to do is make a request
这个程序要做的就是发出一个请求
all the way to this processor and this particular cache
一直到这个处理器和这个特定的缓存
in this processor.
在此处理器中。
And then it gets the data back.
然后它将数据取回。
So what you see here is a round trip access
所以您在这里看到的是往返交通
that goes across the chip.
贯穿芯片。
And this distance, if it's large,
如果这个距离很大，
could take 10s of cycles.
可能需要10秒钟的周期。
So typically, it's a single cycle
所以通常是一个周期
to access local memory-- the fastest local memory,
访问本地内存-最快的本地内存，
called the L1 cache.
称为L1缓存。
But it could take 10s of cycles to go send a message
但是发送消息可能需要10个周期
across the chip and 10s of cycles to get the data back.
跨芯片和10s的周期来获取数据。
So the bottleneck, really, in parallel processing
所以实际上是并行处理的瓶颈
from a standpoint of communication
从沟通的角度
is this routing of messages and getting the messages back.
消息的这种路由并获取消息。
One of the things that my research group is doing
我的研究小组正在做的一件事
is looking at the notion of migrating
正在研究迁移的概念
computation as opposed to data.
计算而非数据。
We call it execution migration, where
我们称其为执行迁移
you could say-- suppose I have a processor running
你可以说-假设我有一个处理器在运行
a particular program, out here.
一个特定的程序，在这里。
And if this program wanted to access a remote memory,
如果该程序想访问远程存储器，
then, rather than doing what I just
然后，而不是做我刚刚做的
showed you there-- send a message,
向您展示了-发送消息，
get the data back-- you could imagine
取回数据-您可以想象
that you could migrate the program itself.
您可以迁移程序本身。
And in particular, you think of it
特别是您想到的
as migrating the context of the program
作为迁移程序的上下文
from this processor to this one.
从这个处理器到这个。
And so what is the context?
那么背景是什么呢？
For those of you who have taken 6.004 probably
对于那些已经采取6.004的人
know what this is.
知道这是什么。
But it's simply where you are in terms
但这只是您所处的位置
of executing your program.
执行程序
And that's typically given to you
这通常是给你的
by our program counter, and your current state of your register
通过我们的程序计数器，以及您当前的注册状态
file, and a few other things, including
文件以及其他一些内容，包括
cache memory and so on and so forth.
缓存等等。
So the advantage with execution migration
因此执行迁移的优势
is that it's a one way trip, as opposed to a round trip.
这是单程旅行，而不是往返旅行。
You don't have to send a message and get the data back,
您不必发送消息并取回数据，
which would be two messages, if you will--
如果您愿意的话，这将是两条消息
one in the case of the address and the other
一个是地址，另一个是
for the data-- but you migrate your execution.
数据-但是您可以迁移执行。
Since you have computation out here,
既然这里有计算
you can run on this remote processor.
您可以在此远程处理器上运行。
So that's one of the advantages of execution migration
这就是执行迁移的优势之一
One of the downsides of it is that this
缺点之一是
can be multiple kilobytes-- or kilobits.
可以是数KB或千位。
And it could be significantly more in terms of size,
就规模而言，可能要大得多，
or in terms of bits, than the data that you want to access.
或以位数表示，而不是要访问的数据。
So there's a trade-off here.
因此，这里需要权衡。
And then, when any time you have a trade-off,
然后，当您需要进行权衡时，
you can think of an algorithm to try and find
您可以想到一种算法来尝试找到
the optimal trade-off.
最佳权衡。
So this is the context for the particular optimization problem
这就是特定优化问题的背景
that we need to solve, here, that corresponds
我们需要解决的，在这里，对应
to really deciding when you want to do data migration
真正决定何时进行数据迁移
and when you want to do execution migration.
以及何时要执行执行迁移。
There's a choice.
有一个选择。
At the top level, it's a round trip to get the data.
在顶层，这是获取数据的往返行程。
So you're really traveling longer-- twice as long.
因此，您实际上要旅行更长的时间-是旅行的两倍。
The distance is twice as much.
距离是原来的两倍。
But it's possible that the amount
但金额可能
of state that you'd have to move,
处于必须移动的状态，
in terms of taking your context of your thread
就线程的上下文而言
and moving across the chip, could be large enough
在芯片上移动可能足够大
that it offsets the advantage of the shorter distance.
它抵消了距离较短的优势。
So we set this up as an optimization problem.
因此，我们将其设置为优化问题。
So now we're in the realm of-- we moved from 6.004 to 6.006,
所以现在我们处于-我们从6.004移至6.006的领域，
here, in the last couple of seconds.
在这里，在最后几秒钟。
So assume we know or can predict the access
因此，假设我们知道或可以预测访问
pattern of a program.
程序的模式。
And you can do this-- people build
你可以做到-人们建立
these things in hardware-- prefetch engines,
这些东西在硬件中-预取引擎，
branch predictors, and so on.
分支预测变量，等等。
They're in the x86 machines.
它们在x86机器中。
And you can tell-- especially if you're going through a loop
而且您可以说出-特别是如果您正在经历循环
over and over-- you can make this prediction.
一遍又一遍-您可以做出此预测。
So you have some amount of look ahead.
因此，您有一些展望。
And you know that m1 through mn are
而且您知道m1到mn是
the memory accesses that this program is going to make.
该程序将要进行的内存访问。
And these other memory addresses.
还有其他这些内存地址。
And I'm going to think about p of m1, p of m2, p of mn,
我将考虑m1的p，m2的p，mn的p
as the processor caches for each mi.
因为处理器为每个mi缓存。
So what might be the case, in a simple example,
在一个简单的例子中，情况可能是这样
is you want to access memory in processor one.
您是否要访问处理器一中的内存？
You're sitting there and you want
你坐在那里，你想要
to access memory in processor one.
访问处理器一中的内存。
And then, the next one, you want to access memory
然后，下一个要访问内存
in processor two.
在处理器二中。
And so on and so forth.
等等等等。
So you might see something like that.
因此，您可能会看到类似的内容。
So the sequence of memory addressees--
因此，内存收件人的顺序-
if you're sitting on processor one-- this first one is local.
如果您坐在处理器一上，那么这第一个是本地的。
And then, after that, you want to access processor two's
然后，在那之后，您要访问处理器二的
memory because you're sharing data with it.
内存，因为您正在与它共享数据。
Then you're back home, again, to processor one.
然后，您再次回到家，去处理一个处理器。
And so on and so forth.
等等等等。
So that's one example of a set up.
这就是设置的一个例子。
And we can think of about the cost of migration
我们可以考虑一下迁移成本
as-- if you want to go from s to d--
如果-如果您想从s转到d-
as being a function of the distance,
作为距离的函数，
s comma d, plus some constant, which
s逗号，加上一些常数，
is proportional to the context size.
与上下文大小成正比。
And that context size, we're going to assume
和那个上下文的大小，我们将假设
is fixed for a particular architecture.
对于特定的体系结构是固定的。
It may change for different architectures,
对于不同的架构，它可能会改变，
but if it's a few kilobits, then there's
但如果只有几千位，那么
going to be some overhead associated
将有一些相关的开销
with putting the context onto the network.
将上下文放到网络上。
And it's a sizable overhead that needs to be taken into account.
这是需要考虑的相当大的开销。
That's the cost of migration.
那就是迁移的成本。
The cost of an access, s comma d,
访问成本，以逗号表示，
is twice the distance between s and d.
是s和d之间距离的两倍。
And it's typically just a word that you
通常这只是一个词
want to access-- 32 bits, 64 bits--
想要访问-32位，64位-
and so there's no additional overhead associated with a data
因此没有与数据相关的额外开销
access.
访问。
So there you go.
所以你去了。
You have the formulation of the problem.
您已经提出了问题。
You have the trade-off written, where the cost of migration
您已编写了权衡，其中迁移成本
has just the distance.
有距离。
But it has a constant factor.
但是它有一个恒定的因素。
And you've got twice the distance, here, for the access.
您的访问距离是这里的两倍。
Now if s equals d, and I want to write this down,
现在，如果s等于d，我想写下来，
you have a local access.
您具有本地访问权限。
And the cost is assumed to be zero.
并且假定成本为零。
You could change that.
您可以更改它。
We are in the realm of the theory and symbols.
我们处于理论和符号的领域。
So you can do whatever you want.
这样您就可以做任何您想做的事。
But given those equations, our problem
但是考虑到这些方程式，我们的问题
is decide when to migrate to minimize total memory access
确定何时迁移以最小化总内存访问
cost.
成本。
So in our example there, I suppose
所以在我们的示例中，我想
we had p1, p2, p2, et cetera.
我们有p1，p2，p2等。
And let's say you start at p1.
假设您从p1开始。
This first one would be a local access.
第一个将是本地访问。
And then, you may decide that you
然后，您可以决定
want to migrate to p2, over here.
想要迁移到此处的p2。
In this case, you get this as a local access, as well.
在这种情况下，您也可以将其作为本地访问权限。
So is this one.
这也是。
Right here, you might want to migrate to p1 back to be p1.
在这里，您可能想要迁移回p1成为p1。
So this becomes a local access.
因此，这成为本地访问。
That's a local access.
那是本地访问。
They're all, essentially, free.
他们基本上都是免费的。
And then, if you just stay at p1,
然后，如果您只是停留在p1，
over here, you may end up doing remote accesses to p3 and p2,
在这里，您可能最终要对p3和p2进行远程访问，
respectively.
分别。
And so you have a cost of migration-- the cost
因此，您需要承担迁移费用-
of migration and the cost of two remote access.
迁移和两次远程访问的成本。
So that's the set up.
这就是设置。
How are we going to solve this problem?
我们将如何解决这个问题？
Are we going Dijkstra?
我们要去迪克斯特拉吗？
Are we going to use Bellman-Ford?
我们要使用贝尔曼福特吗？
Are we going to use balanced search trees?
我们将使用平衡搜索树吗？
Are we going to use hash functions?
我们要使用哈希函数吗？
What are we going to use?
我们要用什么？
AUDIENCE: Dynamic Programming.
听众：动态编程。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: Dynamic Programming.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：动态编程。
All together.
全部一起。
EVERYONE: Dynamic Programming.
所有人：动态编程。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: Dynamic programming, all right.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：好的，动态编程。
We're going to use dynamic programming
我们将使用动态编程
to solve this problem.
解决这个问题。
Good.
好。
So Erik taught you something.
所以埃里克教了你一些东西。
AUDIENCE: Where are the erasers?
听众：橡皮擦在哪里？
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: Yeah.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：是的。
Where are the erasers?
橡皮擦在哪里？
I think they fluttered down here.
我认为他们在这里扑腾。
All right.
好吧。
Let me bail out and use this while you find the erasers.
当您找到橡皮擦时，让我纾困并使用它。
So a program at p1, which is the processor, initially.
因此，最初是处理器p1处的程序。
I'm just going to set up this DP.
我将要设置此DP。
Let's assume that the number of processors equals Q. Now,
假设处理器数量等于Q。现在，
what are the subproblems?
有哪些子问题？
You could do this many different ways.
您可以用许多不同的方法来做。
Let's go ahead and use prefixes.
让我们继续使用前缀。
And so DP(k,p1) is the cost of the optimal solution
因此DP（k，p1）是最优解的成本
for the prefix m1 through mk of memory accesses,
对于内存访问的前缀m1到mk，
when the program starts at p1 and ends at pi.
当程序从p1开始并在pi结束时。
So that's my subproblem.
这就是我的子问题。
I want to know, as I build this up,
我想知道，随着我的成长，
what is the optimal way that I'm going
我要去的最佳方式是什么
to choose between migrations and accesses
在迁移和访问之间进行选择
for the first k memory access, assuming a starting point at p1
对于第一个k存储器访问，假设起始点为p1
and ending at some pi.
并在某个圆周率结束。
And I need to build up these subproblems.
我需要建立这些子问题。
And I want to grow them.
我想种植它们。
Let's go ahead and set this up.
让我们继续进行设置。
What I want to do now is figure out DP(k plus 1, pj).
我现在想做的就是找出DP（k加1，pj）。
And assuming I have all of the k, pi's computed--
并假设我拥有所有的k，pi的计算公式为-
and how many subproblems do I have?
我有几个子问题？
How many subproblems do I have?
Total?
总？
Look at this and tell me what the ranges of the possibilities
看看这个，告诉我可能性的范围是多少
are.
是。
So how many subproblems would I have?
那么我会有几个子问题？
Someone?
有人吗
N times Q. So you have N times Q subproblems.
N乘Q。所以您有N乘Q子问题。
So you've set this up for up until k and for all
因此，您将其设置为最多k个
of the pi's.
的PI。
Now, what you have to do is essentially say, well,
现在，您要做的基本上是说，
DP of k plus 1, pj is going to be k, pj plus cost of access
DP的k加1，pj将为k，pj加上访问成本
pj, p of mk plus 1 if pj is not equal to p of mk plus 1.
pj，如果pj不等于mk的p加1，则mk的p加1。
So there's going to be two cases.
因此，将有两种情况。
I'll just write this out and I'll explain it.
我将其写出来，并对其进行解释。
But the first case corresponds to if the new memory
但是第一种情况对应于新的内存
access is not in the processor cache corresponding to pj,
访问不在与pj对应的处理器缓存中，
then what you could do is use the optimum value,
那么您可以做的就是使用最佳值，
where you ended pj, and simply do a remote access that
您在哪里结束了pj，只需进行远程访问即可
corresponds to accessing mk plus 1.
对应于访问mk加1。
So that's one case.
这就是一种情况。
The case is to use the minimum solution-- optimum solution
情况是使用最小的解决方案-最佳解决方案
corresponding to ending at pi and do a migration.
对应于以pi结尾并进行迁移。
You have cost of migration from pi to pj.
您需要从pi迁移到pj。
And you do this if you want to go do p of mk
如果您想去做mk的操作，就可以这样做
plus 1-- the processor corresponding to p
加1-对应于p的处理器
of mk plus 1.
的mk加1。
So that's the set up for this dynamic program.
这就是该动态程序的设置。
What you've done is created a sub problem, its optimum,
您所做的事情会产生一个子问题，即最佳问题，
and then you look at the two cases.
然后看看这两种情况。
You want to go migrate and do a local access-- that's
您想迁移并进行本地访问-
this case over here.
这个案例在这里。
Migrate to the processor and do a local access there.
迁移到处理器并在那里进行本地访问。
That will be this case.
就是这种情况。
And in this case, you stay where you are and do a remote access.
在这种情况下，您将留在原处并进行远程访问。
In the case of migration, you could end up choosing different
在迁移的情况下，您最终可能会选择其他
initial starting points corresponding to the pi's.
对应于pi的初始起点。
And you have to run through all of those.
而您必须经历所有这些。
So what's the cost of a subproblem, or the running time
那么子问题的成本或运行时间是多少
of computing one of these things-- it's order?
计算这些东西之一-是命令？
Q. And so the total cost is NQ squared.
问：因此总成本为NQ平方。
It's a little review of DP.
这是对DP的一些评论。
I'm going to stop here and let Erik take over.
我要在这里停下来，让埃里克接任。
Just, in closing, while this makes some assumptions,
最后，尽管做出了一些假设，
It's actually fairly close to what
它实际上与
we're building in hardware.
我们正在硬件中构建。
This type of analysis is something
这种类型的分析是
that we have to do in hardware.
我们必须在硬件上做的。
My research group is building a 128 processor machine,
我的研究小组正在建造一台128处理器的机器，
that we call the Execution Migration Machine.
我们称之为执行迁移机器。
And it does exactly what I've described to you,
它完全符合我对您的描述，
decide whether to do a remote access
决定是否进行远程访问
or to do a migration based on this kind of analysis.
或基于这种分析进行迁移。
So hand it over to Erik.
因此，将其交给Erik。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: I have a microphone.
埃里克·迪迈因教授：我有麦克风。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: All right.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：好的。
Good.
好。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: So I have a few things
埃里克·迪梅因教授：所以我有几件事
to tell you a little bit about.
告诉你一些有关。
Srini talked about one topic in detail.
Srini详细讨论了一个主题。
I'm going to talk about many topics in less detail,
我将不那么详细地谈论许多主题，
as I said "shallowly."
就像我说的那样。
And these are my main areas of research.
这些是我的主要研究领域。
I do geometry, in particular, folding, and data structures,
我做几何，尤其是折叠和数据结构，
graphs, and recreational algorithms.
图和休闲算法。
That's the really fun stuff.
那是真正有趣的东西。
A lot of these have corresponding courses
其中很多都有相应的课程
if you're interested in more about this stuff.
如果您对这些东西有更多的兴趣。
Computational geometry, in general,
一般而言，计算几何
is-- I'm not going to remember all numbers.
是-我不会记住所有数字。
840?
840？
50?
50吗
50.
6.850.
6.850。
That's a class I don't teach.
那是我不教的课。
Folding is 6.849.
折叠为6.849。
Data Structures is 6.851.
数据结构为6.851。
And Graphs was being taught this semester,
这个学期正在教Graphs，
in parallel with this class.
与此类并行。
6.889.
6.889。
And recreational algorithms isn't fully covered
娱乐算法并未完全涵盖
but you could check out SP.268, which
但是您可以签出SP.268，
was offered last semester.
是上学期提供的。
And especially for those watching at home
特别是对于那些在家看的人
on MIT OpenCourseWare-- this class,
在MIT OpenCourseWare上-此类
all the video lectures are online for free.
所有视频讲座都是免费在线。
6.851, we'll do that next semester.
6.851，我们将在下个学期进行。
And 6.889 are all online, right now.
现在，6.889都在线。
And there's some lecture notes for SP.268 on OpenCourseWare.
在OpenCourseWare上有一些SP.268的讲义。
There's a lot of material, here.
这里有很多材料。
And in particular, the obvious next class for you to be taking
尤其是显而易见的下一堂课
is 6.046.
是6.046。
But why should you be taking 6.046?
但是为什么要服用6.046？
Because then you can take all these exciting classes
因为这样您可以参加所有这些令人兴奋的课程
and many others about algorithms.
还有许多其他关于算法的知识。
There's a complete list of follow-on classes
有完整的后续课程清单
in the lecture notes, which are online.
在在线的讲义中。
And there's a ton of-- there's so much research in algorithms.
而且，有大量的算法研究。
It's a really exciting area.
这是一个非常令人兴奋的领域。
This is just the beginning-- just a taste.
这仅仅是开始-只是一种味道。
And I want to show you various exciting places it can go.
我想向您展示它可以去的各种令人兴奋的地方。
Let's do some algorithms.
让我们做一些算法。
So the first topic I'll tell you a little bit
所以我首先告诉你一些话题
about-- maybe the most fun-- is geometric folding algorithms.
关于-也许最有趣的是-几何折叠算法。
That's the title of the textbook and the class 6.849.
那是教科书的标题和6.849的班级。
And in general-- well, there's a lot
总体而言-嗯，有很多
of different kinds of folding, in the world,
世界上各种各样的折叠
but maybe the most accessible and fun is origami.
但也许最容易接近和有趣的是折纸。
So you have, on the one hand, a piece of paper.
因此，一方面，您有一张纸。
And you'd like to turn it into some crazy, three dimensional
而您想将其变成疯狂的三维
shape, which I'm not going to try to draw here.
形状，在这里我不会尝试绘制。
You want to fold a giraffe or you
您想折叠长颈鹿还是
want to make some geometric sculpture.
想做一些几何雕塑。
How do you do this?
你怎么做到这一点？
So, usually, you put some creases into the piece of paper
因此，通常，您在纸上放置一些折痕
in some reasonable way.
以某种合理的方式。
And one of the questions is what are
问题之一是
the rules for putting creases into a piece of paper?
将折痕放入纸的规则是什么？
When is that possible?
什么时候可能？
And then you'd like to fold it into that shape.
然后，您想将其折叠成该形状。
So there are really two big problems here.
因此，这里确实存在两个大问题。
One is I guess you could call it foldability.
一种是我猜您可以称其为可折叠性。
And this is what you do if you practice origami
这就是练习折纸的方法
in the typical way.
以典型的方式。
You get origami diagrams, and they say, "fold this."
您会看到折纸图，他们说，“将其折叠”。
And you're like, oh, gosh.
你就像，天哪。
Takes you hours to figure out how to fold something.
需要花费几个小时来弄清楚如何折叠东西。
Especially, if they just gave you a crease pattern.
特别是，如果他们只是给您一个折痕图案。
Can you even tell does it fold into anything, first of all.
首先，您能否说出它是否折叠成任何东西。
And then, if so, how do I do it?
然后，如果是这样，我该怎么做？
That problem-- folding increase pattern and understanding
这个问题-折叠增加模式和理解
what crease patterns are valid-- unfortunately, is NP-complete.
哪些折痕模式有效-不幸的是，NP完全。
So there's no good way to really understand that.
因此，没有真正了解这一点的好方法。
So origami is hard.
所以折纸很难。
In some sense, the more interesting direction,
从某种意义上说，更有趣的方向
though, is the reverse direction,
虽然是相反的方向
which I would call origami design.
我将其称为折纸设计。
I have an intended 3D shape I want to design.
我有一个想要设计的预期3D形状。
How can I come up with-- how can I, as an algorithm, convert
我该怎么想-我如何才能将算法转换为
that 3D shape into a crease pattern that does fold,
3D形状变成可以折叠的折痕图案，
that's guaranteed to fold into that 3D shape.
保证可以折叠成3D形状。
And that's actually solvable.
这实际上是可以解决的。
So design is easier.
因此设计更容易。
And there's all sorts of different versions
各种各样的版本
of the design problem.
设计问题。
Some of them, you could solve in polynomial time.
其中一些，您可以在多项式时间内求解。
Some of them, you can't.
其中一些，你不能。
If you really want optimal design,
如果您真的想要最佳设计，
that can be NP-complete again.
可以再次完成NP。
But in particular, there's a way to fold any 3D shape you want.
但特别是，有一种方法可以折叠您想要的任何3D形状。
So there's an algorithm-- the coolest one, right now,
因此，有一种算法-目前最酷的算法
is called Origamizer.
被称为Origamizer。
It's free software online, by Tomohiro Tachi.
它是Tomohiro Tachi的在线免费软件。
And you give it a 3D model of a polyhedron.
然后给它一个多面体的3D模型。
And it outputs a giant crease pattern
并输出巨大的折痕
on a square piece of paper that folds into that 3D polyhedron.
在一张折叠成3D多面体的正方形纸上。
And it's reasonably practical.
而且这是相当实用的。
And he's folded tons of models in that way.
他以这种方式折叠了许多模型。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
I'll show you some other things.
我会告诉你其他的事情。
Here's a simple example of a geometric origami model.
这是一个几何折纸模型的简单示例。
So this is folded from a square paper with concentric squares
所以这是从具有同心正方形的正方形纸上折叠的
as creases.
折痕。
Alternating mountain and valley.
交替的山脉和山谷。
So you see mountain valley, mountain valley.
所以你看到山谷，山谷。
Also fold the diagonals.
还要折叠对角线。
It's very easy to make.
制作起来很容易。
And what's funny-- what's cool about it
有趣的是-有趣的是
is that when you put all those creases in,
当你把所有这些折痕放进去时
it pops into this 3D shape, which for many years people
它变成这种3D形状，多年来人们
conjectured was a hyperbolic parabola.
推测是双曲线抛物线。
This design is one of the earliest geometric origami
这种设计是最早的几何折纸之一
designs.
设计。
It goes back to late '20s in the Bauhaus School of Design.
它可以追溯到20年代后期的包豪斯设计学院。
And it's very cool.
而且非常酷。
People fold them a lot.
人们将它们折叠很多。
I've personally folded thousands of them
我亲自折叠了数千个
for sculpture and things.
雕塑和事物。
We also do a lot of algorithmic sculpture, which
我们还做了很多算法雕塑，
I won't talk about in detail here.
在这里我不会详细讨论。
But we discovered, two years ago, that this does not exist.
但是两年前我们发现这不存在。
It is impossible to fold a square piece of paper
不可能折叠一张正方形的纸
with this crease pattern.
这种折痕样式。
That was a bit of a surprise.
这有点令人惊讶。
And it's kind of fun to make things that don't exist.
制作不存在的东西是一种乐趣。
AUDIENCE: So what is that?
听众：那是什么？
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: So what is this?
ERIK DEMAINE教授：那是什么？
Well, somehow, physical world is differing from the real world.
好吧，某种程度上，物理世界与现实世界有所不同。
Now, some ways it might be differing
现在，在某些方面可能有所不同
are that these creases might not be
这些折痕可能不是
creases in the technical sense.
技术意义上的折痕。
A crease is a place that should be non-differentiable.
折痕是一个不应有差异的地方。
So maybe they're kind of rounding it out.
因此，也许他们正在四舍五入。
And then, who knows what's happening.
然后，谁知道发生了什么事。
Then, kind of all bets are off.
然后，所有赌注都关闭了。
Another possibility of what I think is happening
我认为正在发生的另一种可能性
is that their are extra creases, in here, that you don't see.
是它们是多余的折痕，在这里看不到。
They're very small.
他们很小。
If you look, especially the raw edge, here, and that profile.
如果您看这里，尤其是原始边缘，以及该轮廓。
It's a little bit wavy.
有点波浪。
And it's conceivable there's some points here
可以想象这里有几点
that look non-differentiable to me.
对我来说，这是不可区分的。
And I always thought I wasn't folding it well enough.
我一直以为我折叠得不够好。
But in fact, something like that has to happen.
但是实际上，类似的事情必须发生。
And my conjecture is, if you look
我的推测是，如果你看
at this under a microscope, which we haven't done yet,
在显微镜下，我们还没有做过
there are little creases that are so shallow they're
有些小折痕太浅了
hard to see, but are there.
很难看，但是在那里。
And the theorem says some creases have to be there.
定理说必须有一些折痕。
It is possible to fold this with extra creases,
可以用额外的折痕折叠它，
but not with these.
但是这些却不行。
So get rid of that.
所以摆脱它。
On the other hand, if you do the same thing
另一方面，如果您做同样的事情
with concentric circular creases-- this a little harder
同心圆形折痕-这有点难
to unfold.
展开。
It really wants to be in this kind of Pringles shape.
它真的想成为这种品客薯片形状。
This also is from about Bauhaus.
这也来自包豪斯。
It's a little harder to fold concentric circles.
折叠同心圆比较困难。
But this, we think, does exist.
但是我们认为确实存在。
Can't prove it yet.
尚无法证明。
So we've done a lot of sculpture based on these guys.
因此，我们基于这些人做了很多雕塑。
What else do I want to say?
我还要说什么？
Another demo.
另一个演示。
So here's a fun problem.
所以这是一个有趣的问题。
This is a magic trick.
这是一个魔术。
Goes back to Houdini and others.
回到Houdini和其他人。
So imagine I take a rectangle of paper and then I fold it flat
想象一下，我取一个矩形的纸，然后将其折平
and take my scissors-- not strict origami, here--
拿我的剪刀-这里不是严格的折纸-
and I make one complete straight cut.
然后我就完成了一个完整的直切
In this case, I get two pieces.
在这种情况下，我得到了两块。
And I unfold the pieces.
然后我展开作品。
And the question is what shapes can I get out of those pieces?
问题是我可以从这些零件中得到什么形状？
In this case, I get a swan.
在这种情况下，我得到了天鹅。
You're not impressed so I'll another one.
您没有留下深刻的印象，所以我再给一个。
Make one straight cut.
进行一次直切。
These are on my web page if you want
如果需要，这些都在我的网页上
to impress all your friends.
打动你所有的朋友。
You could take the class if you want to know how it's done.
如果您想知道如何完成课程，可以上课。
This example has a lot of symmetry.
这个例子有很多对称性。
You get a little angelfish.
你会得到一个小神仙鱼。
I only have one more example.
我只有一个例子。
I hope you'll be impressed.
希望您会印象深刻。
This is very hard to fold.
这很难折。
It was an MIT spotlight picture, at some point.
在某些时候，这是麻省理工学院的一大亮点。
And it's even harder to cut.
而且更难切割。
Straight cut.
直切。
This should be the MIT logo.
这应该是MIT徽标。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
So the theorem is there's an algorithm, given
因此定理有一个算法，给定
any set of polygons in the plane,
平面中的任何一组多边形
you could fold, make one straight cut,
你可以折叠，直切
and get exactly those polygons.
并精确地获得这些多边形。
There's some limits, in practice,
实际上有一些限制
because of paper thickness.
由于纸张厚度。
But in theory, you can do everything.
但是从理论上讲，您可以做所有事情。
All right.
好吧。
Fun stuff.
好玩的东西。
I don't think I have time to talk about self-assembly.
我认为我没有时间谈论自组装。
Let me talk a little bit about data structures because,
让我谈谈数据结构，因为，
conveniently, Srini drew this diagram for me.
斯里尼方便地为我画了这张图。
And I have the exact same diagram-- the left one, though.
我有完全一样的图-但是左边的图。
I'm old fashioned.
我是老式的。
So the models of computation we've used, in this class,
因此，我们在此类中使用的计算模型
are pretty simple.
非常简单。
We have, in particular, the Word RAM.
我们尤其拥有Word RAM。
You can read a word.
你会读一个字。
You can add two words.
您可以添加两个单词。
Do whatever you want with a constant number words.
使用常量数字单词可以做任何您想做的事情。
Send them out to main memory.
将它们发送到主存储器。
Everything's the same amount of time.
一切都是一样的时间。
It's all constant, anyway, so who cares?
无论如何，这都是恒定的，那么谁在乎呢？
Except there's this issue in real computers,
除非实际计算机中存在此问题，
and it gets even worse with parallel, but let's
并行处理会变得更糟，但是让我们
stick to sequential old fashioned computers.
坚持使用顺序的老式计算机。
So you have this slow bottleneck between main memory and cache.
因此，您在主内存和缓存之间存在缓慢的瓶颈。
Cache is really fast.
缓存确实非常快。
Think of this as a really fat pipe.
认为这是一个非常胖的管道。
And this is a very thin pipe.
这是一个非常细的管道。
What do we do?
我们做什么？
We'd like to always work with things in cache,
我们希望始终使用缓存中的内容，
but that's kind of difficult.
但这有点困难。
At some point, you run out of space.
在某些时候，您空间不足。
You've got to go to main memory.
您必须进入主存储器。
And maybe to disc, other levels of the memory hierarchy.
也许是光盘，其他层次的内存层次结构。
So what systems do is, when you fetch something from memory,
所以系统要做的是，当您从内存中获取某些东西时，
you don't just get one word, you get an entire cache line.
您不仅得到一个单词，还获得了整个缓存行。
And cache lines are getting bigger and bigger.
缓存行越来越大。
But memory transfers happen in blocks,
但是内存传输是分块进行的
when you're going to a big memory.
当您要记忆大的时候。
So let's say B is the size of a block.
假设B是一个块的大小。
There is another model of computation
还有另一种计算模型
that's more sophisticated than the Word RAM that
比Word RAM更复杂
says how should my running time depend on B. How many memory
说我的跑步时间应该如何取决于B。多少内存
transfers do I need to do, as a function of B and n?
我需要做转移，作为B和n的函数吗？
And so for example, if you want to do search-- normally,
例如，如果您要进行搜索-通常，
we think of doing binary search.
我们考虑进行二进制搜索。
That takes log(n) accesses if everything is uniform.
如果一切都统一，则需要log（n）访问。
But with asymmetry, and if you're
但是不对称，如果你
reading in entire blocks, if you do it right,
整本阅读，如果做得对，
you can do it in log base B of n, instead of log base 2.
您可以在n的日志基数B中进行操作，而不是在日志基数2中进行操作。
This is counting memory transfers, not computation.
这是在计算内存传输，而不是计算。
Computation here is free.
这里的计算是免费的。
It's a little weird, but you get used to it.
有点奇怪，但是您已经习惯了。
Sorting.
排序。
They're classic.
他们很经典。
Just to give you an idea of how this gets a little complicated.
只是为了让您了解这如何变得有点复杂。
You get n divided by B times log base C of n divided by B. C
您得到n除以B乘以n的对数基数C除以B。
is the number of blocks that fit in here.
是此处适合的块数。
So there's C different blocks that fit in your cache.
因此，您的缓存中有C个不同的块。
That's the optimal way to sort.
这是最佳的排序方式。
Just upper and lower bounds in the comparison model.
比较模型中的上下限。
Just to give you a flavor.
只是为了给您一种味道。
And there's a whole study of algorithms to do this.
并且对此进行了完整的算法研究。
What's really cool is you can achieve these bounds
真正酷的是您可以实现这些界限
even if you don't know what B is.
即使您不知道B是什么。
And if you don't know what C is.
而且，如果您不知道C是什么。
There's one algorithm, that whatever the architecture is
有一种算法，无论架构如何
underlying it, we'll still achieve the same bounds.
作为基础，我们仍将达到相同的界限。
Those are called cache-oblivious algorithms,
这些被称为“缓存不注意”算法，
and they were invented, here, at MIT.
它们是在麻省理工学院发明的。
I think I want to-- this is too much fun to pass up.
我想我想-这真是太有趣了。
On the Word RAM, there's this problem,
在Word RAM上，存在此问题，
which we've dealt with several times.
我们已经处理了好几次了。
What if you want to maintain a dynamic set of elements--
如果您要维护一组动态元素怎么办-
integers.
整数。
I want to do insert, delete, predecessor, successor.
我想做插入，删除，前任，后继。
This is what binary search trees do.
这就是二进制搜索树的作用。
But you can do better.
但是你可以做得更好。
If we have integers-- n integers-- in the range
如果我们有整数-n个整数-在范围内
0 to u minus 1.
0至u减1。
So u is the size of the universe.
所以你就是宇宙的大小。
Then, we already know how to do log(n).
然后，我们已经知道如何执行log（n）。
But you can do two bounds.
但是您可以做两个界限。
One is log(log(u)).
一种是log（log（u））。
This is a data structure called [INAUDIBLE].
这是一个称为[音频]的数据结构。
And it's in CLRS, if you're interested.
如果您有兴趣，它位于CLRS中。
You can also do log(log(n)) divided by log(log(u)).
您还可以执行log（log（n））除以log（log（u））。
This is a data structure called fusion trees.
这是一个称为融合树的数据结构。
It's an advanced data structure.
这是一个高级数据结构。
6.851, if you're interested.
6.851，如果您有兴趣。
And you can take the min of those two.
您可以选择两者中的最小值。
That's, essentially, the best possible,
从本质上讲，那是最好的，
the matching lower bound, that that that's
匹配的下界
all you can achieve.
您所能实现的。
And so just to state it in terms that you know,
因此，仅以您知道的术语来陈述，
which is normal n bounds.
这是正常的n界。
You take the min of those two things,
你拿这两件事中的最小值，
there are always at most square root log(n) divided
总有最多平方根log（n）除
by log(log(n)).
通过log（log（n））。
Compare that with log(n).
将其与log（n）进行比较。
It's way better.
更好。
A whole square root better.
整个平方根更好。
And a little tiny savings better.
还有一点点的节省更好。
And this is optimal.
这是最佳的。
It is a function of n.
它是n的函数。
That's the best you can do for the predecessor problem.
这是您对前任问题所能做的最好的事情。
So pretty crazy stuff.
太疯狂了。
It's a very complicated structure.
这是一个非常复杂的结构。
It's probably completely impractical.
这可能是完全不切实际的。
But, hey.
但是，嘿。
They're, theoretically, pretty cool.
从理论上讲，它们非常酷。
I'll tell you a little bit about graph algorithms.
我会告诉您一些有关图算法的知识。
We've seen a lot of graph algorithms in this class.
在此类中，我们已经看到了很多图算法。
One way to make them new and fun again is to suppose your graph
让它们重新变得有趣的一种方法是假设您的图表
is planar or almost planer.
是平面的或几乎是平面的。
Meaning you can draw it in two dimensions
意味着您可以将其绘制为二维
without any crossings, as you might get from a graph that's
没有任何交叉，因为您可能会从
drawn on the earth, like a road network
像路网一样画在地上
or something with no or few overpasses.
或没有或几乎没有立交桥的东西。
Then you can do things a lot better.
然后，您可以做得更好。
For example, you can do the equivalent
例如，您可以做等效的
of Dijkstra's algorithm.
Dijkstra的算法。
So non-negative weight shortest path, in linear time.
因此，非负权重最短路径是线性时间。
That's not so impressive cause Dijkstra is number of edges.
这并不是那么令人印象深刻，因为Dijkstra的边缘数量很多。
Here, I mean number of vertices.
在这里，我的意思是顶点数。
It doesn't really matter with planar graphs.
平面图并不重要。
And we had E log(V).
我们有E log（V）。
You can write E, here, if you prefer.
如果愿意，可以在此处写E。
It's only a log savings.
这只是节省的日志。
More impressive, is you can do with negative weights--
更令人印象深刻的是，您可以负负重做
the equivalent of Bellman-Ford-- in almost linear time.
在几乎线性的时间内相当于Bellman-Ford。
So some log factors.
因此，一些日志因素。
Log squared n divided by log(log(n)).
对数平方n除以log（log（n））。
It's the best bound known to date.
这是迄今为止已知的最佳界限。
That was a result from last year.
那是去年的结果。
So it's still a work in progress.
因此，它仍在进行中。
And if you're interested in this kind of stuff,
如果您对这种东西感兴趣，
you should check out the videos for the class we just taught,
您应该查看我们刚刚讲授的课程的视频，
6.889.
6.889。
And recreation algorithms.
和娱乐算法。
I've actually already told you about a lot
我实际上已经告诉过你很多
of these-- like algorithms for solving a Rubik's cube in n
其中的-像解决n中的魔方的算法
squared divided by log(n) steps.
平方除以log（n）步骤。
That was a paper this year.
那是今年的一篇论文。
Tetris is NP-complete.
俄罗斯方块是NP完全的。
A whole bunch of NP-completeness, and x time
一大堆NP完整性和x时间
completeness, and so on.
完整性等等。
Results for games.
游戏结果。
Other fun stuff, like balloon twisting-- algorithms
其他有趣的东西，例如气球扭曲算法
for designing how to balloon twist a given polyhedron,
设计如何对给定的多面体进行气球变形
optimally, using the fewest balloons.
最佳地，使用最少的气球。
Algorithmic magic tricks.
算法魔术。
There's tons of stuff out there.
那里有很多东西。
It's really fun.
真的很好玩。
I should teach a class about some of those things,
我应该教一些这样的事情，
but I haven't yet.
但我还没有
The last thing we wanted to do is together.
我们要做的最后一件事是在一起。
And it has to do with these
这与这些有关
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: Getting rid of these--
SRINI DEVADAS教授：摆脱这些-
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: These cushions.
ERIK DEMAINE教授：这些垫子。
Getting rid of these damn cushions.
摆脱这些该死的靠垫。
We have so many of these cushions.
我们有很多这样的垫子。
Just gotta get rid of them.
只是要摆脱他们。
That's two freebies.
那是两个免费赠品。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: Now, you're
SRINI DEVADAS教授：现在，您
going to have to pay for these cushions.
将不得不支付这些垫子。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: He's kidding.
埃里克·迪迈因教授：他在开玩笑。
He's kidding.
他在开玩笑。
Actually we're having trouble.
其实我们遇到了麻烦。
We're having trouble giving them away
我们很难把他们送走
because-- I don't know-- some people seem
因为-我不知道-有些人似乎
to not like them very much.
不太喜欢他们
And neither do we.
我们也没有。
So we wanted to give you some motivation for why you really
所以我们想给你一些动力，为什么你真的
need some of these cushions.
需要一些垫子。
So we actually prepared a top 10 list.
因此，我们实际上准备了前十名。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: This is the top 10
SRINI DEVADAS教授：这是前十名
uses of 6.006 cushions.
使用6.006垫子。
We're going to alternate here.
我们将在这里替代。
Number 10.
10号
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: You can sit on it
埃里克·迪迈因教授：您可以坐在上面
and get guaranteed inspiration in constant time.
并在固定时间内获得有保证的灵感。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: Don't forget
SRINI DEVADAS教授：不要忘记
to bring one for the final exam.
带一个参加期末考试。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: Highly recommended it.
ERIK DEMAINE教授：强烈推荐。
Number nine.
第九号。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: You can use it as a Frisbee.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：您可以将其用作飞盘。
You've seen that before, except you cut it into a circle.
您之前已经看过，除了将它切成一个圆圈。
You cut it into a circle.
你把它切成一个圈。
And it works really well.
而且效果很好。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: We had fun with a Bandsaw, last night.
埃里克·迪迈恩教授：昨晚，我们在带锯机上玩得很开心。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: Number eight.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：第八名。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: You can sell it
ERIK DEMAINE教授：您可以出售
as a limited edition collectible on eBay.
作为eBay上的限量版收藏品。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: It's never
SRINI DEVADAS教授：从来没有
ever going to be made, again.
再一次。
You can make money off this in 5 years-- 10 years.
您可以在5年至10年内从中赚钱。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: At least $5.
ERIK DEMAINE教授：至少$ 5。
I don't know.
我不知道。
Number seven.
七号
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: Number seven.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：第七名。
If you had two of these, you could stick them like this,
如果您有两个，可以像这样粘贴
and remove the branding, and use it as a regular cushion.
并删除商标，并将其用作常规垫子。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: Now, no one
埃里克·迪迈因教授：现在，没有人
will ever know you took this class.
永远不会知道你参加了这堂课。
You just need two.
您只需要两个。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: Number six.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：第六名。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: Number six.
埃里克·迪梅因教授：第六名。
It's a holiday conversation starter.
这是一个假期谈话的开始。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: And conversation stopper.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：和谈话的阻止者。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: Number five.
埃里克·迪梅因教授：第五名。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: Asymptotically
SRINI DEVADAS教授：渐近地
optimal-- we had to use that term,
最佳-我们必须使用该术语，
acoustic acoustic paneling.
隔音板。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: That was a suggestion from a student.
埃里克·迪梅因教授：这是一个学生的建议。
You just need a lot of them.
您只需要其中的很多。
This would be great for piano, guitar fingering practice.
这对于钢琴，吉他指法练习非常有用。
You know you're doing your DP.
您知道您正在执行DP。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: Number four.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：四号。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: Number four.
ERIK DEMAINE教授：第四名。
You can use it as target practice for your next larp
您可以将其用作下一个练习的目标练习
session.
会议。
Woah.
哇。
Misfire.
失火。
I'm missing.
我迷路了。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: You haven't hit me yet.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：您还没有打我。
All right.
好吧。
Finally, you got one.
最后，您得到了一个。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: Number three.
ERIK DEMAINE教授：第三名。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: All right.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：好的。
10 years from now, it might be all
从现在开始的十年后
you remember about double 0 6.
您还记得两倍0 6。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: In truth, you
埃里克·迪迈因教授：实际上，你
might also remember this top 10 list.
也许还记得这个前10名名单。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: All right.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：好的。
Number two.
第二。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: Number two.
ERIK DEMAINE教授：第二名。
You can use it as your final exam cheat sheet.
您可以将其用作期末考试备忘单。
This is a new rule.
这是一条新规则。
Instead of 8 and 1/2 by 11, you could
而不是8和1/2乘11，您可以
bring in the appropriate number of cushions.
携带适当数量的垫子。
And the number one-- number one use for a double 0 6 cushion.
第一位-第一位使用双0 6垫子。
PROFESSOR SRINI DEVADAS: Three words.
SRINI DEVADAS教授：三个词。
OK Cupid profile picture.
OK丘比特头像。
Don't use this cheat sheet.
不要使用该备忘单。
But come to the final exam and good luck.
但是参加期末考试并祝您好运。
PROFESSOR ERIK DEMAINE: Thanks.
埃里克·迪迈因教授：谢谢。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]